For 3.5 million community health workers,
medicine begins here.
Aïcha is a community health worker.
Today, she sees Mariam.
14 months old. Fever. Lethargic.
Her guide: a 200-page paper protocol.
And zero network.
A bad triage decision:
1 child dies preventably every minute. — WHO
Aïcha needs a doctor. Now.
But the doctor is 80 km away.
This is MediBoussole.
100% offline. No data
ever leaves the phone.
She speaks her own language.
Wolof, Bambara, Fula, French — it doesn't matter.
One photo. Gemma 4 sees
what Aïcha sees.
Gemma 4 E4B —
native multimodal, on-device.
RAG: every answer is grounded
in WHO protocols.
Red triage. Criteria: high fever,
lethargy, moderate dehydration.
Gemma 4 function calling:
SMS auto-generated.
The SMS goes out via 2G.
No internet required.
Twenty minutes later. Mariam is on her way.
The doctor is already waiting.
The doctor receives a structured
clinical summary. She already knows.
3.5 million CHWs.
A €150 Android phone. Zero internet required.
MediBoussole doesn't replace Aïcha.
It amplifies her.
MediBoussole · Built on Gemma 4 + Ollama
Open source · CC-BY 4.0